# JAMES CAMERON-BURN | CV

Senior Software Engineer

Birth Name: James Cockburn

PhD Thesis: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1707.08221

Core Skills: Python, AWS, CI/CD, IaC, Docker, SQL, TypeScript

Glasgow, Scotland james.cameronburn@icloud.com +44 7595 165202

#### **Summary**

I am a self-motivated and passionate software engineer with a wide range of experience in modern software engineering technologies and practices. I have a penchant for learning and for making other people's lives easier through the use of technology.

# **Professional Experience**

#### Senior Software Engineer, Platform/DevEx Team - Wayflyer

July 2022 - present

- · Fully designed and implemented an anonymise-then-clone system for developers to safely and efficiently test against production data locally
- · Fully designed and implemented a regression test system leveraging that functionality, opening a whole range of new testing capabilities
- · Proactively overhauled the authentication system for the main application, discovering and closing a critical vulnerability along the way
- · Implemented fundamental changes to the signup process to improve end-user experience and data quality

#### Senior Software Engineer, Platform/DevEx Team - Skyscanner

Sep 2017 - July 2022

- · Independently implemented a process for language version migrations, enabling 300 services to move from Python 3.6 before it became end of life
- · Introduced CI-time Docker Image acceptance tests to proactively catch regressions
- $\cdot$  Designed and implemented the cross-AWS-account orchestration layer for the in-house CD tool
- · Maintained and improved in-house microservice libraries and Docker base images for Python, Java and Node.js

# **Side Projects Experience**

#### Sole Technical Contributor/Full Stack Software Engineer - My Money Mage

October 2024 - present

- · Full and continuous technical responsibility of a service for financial management, mymoneymage.com
- · Technologies include: Next.js, Golang, ReactJS with react-router, AWS and AuthO

# Sole Technical Contributor/Full Stack Software Engineer - Learn with Dr Laura

July 2023 - present

- · Full and continuous technical responsibility of a professional tutoring business, learnwithdrlaura.com
- · Fully designed and implemented all aspects, including static marketing content and an authenticated user-facing application for lesson management
- · Technologies include: nginx, Vue.js, FastAPI, AWs Route 53, AWS DynamoDB, AWS EC2, AWS SES, AWS Cognito and Python asyncio

### **Education**

#### PhD Student in Theoretical Particle Physics - University of Edinburgh

Aug 2013 - Sep 2017

- · Mathematical calculations of particle collision events within the High Energy Jets (HEJ) framework
- · C++ implementation of numerical integration techniques, developed within the existing HEJ framework

#### MSci Theoretical Physics - University College London

Aug 2009 - Aug 2013

- · Graduated with First-Class Honours
- · Embedded Master's project included learning C++ from scratch to rewrite a FORTRAN codebase to perform quantum mechanical calculations